

LEJEUNE Arnaud

Data Scientist - Machine Learning Engineer

www.alejeune.com
arnaudlejeune44@gmail.com | +33 (0)7 85 41 15 68

/ Programming (Imperative, OOP ...)

/ Database Management (SQL)

Summary

Young French data scientist. Machine & deep learning enthusiast, occasional kaggler.

Looking for a data scientist position for August 2019 in Montréal, Canada.

Already selected and applied for a 2-year Working Holiday Visa (PVT)

Skills

Tools & Frameworks:

/ Pandas / TensorFlow / Scikit-Learn / Keras / Spark / AWS / GCloud / MongoDB / Ubuntu / UNIX

Programming Languages:

/ Python / Java / Scala / WEB

Spoken Languages:

/ French : mother tongue / English : Fluent (TOEIC 965)

Interest

/ 2016 – 2017 President of IMT Atlantique's student's union.

/ Handball goalkeeper in university league. Tennis player for more than 10 years

Education

Big Data & ML Post Master Degree 2018 - Jun 2019 Institut Polytechnique de Paris - Télécom ParisTech (Paris, France) / Machine Learning (Sup. & Unsup.) / Advanced Statistics / Data Engineering (Spark & Hadoop) / NoSQL Systems (MongoDB, Neo4J, ...) / Deep Learning theory / Data Visualization / Text & Image Recognition (CNN, RNN) / Reinforcement Learning (Bandit, QL ...) **Engineering Master's Degree** 2015 - 2018 IMT Atlantique (Nantes, France) Major: Organization & Management of Information Technology / Business Intelligence / IT systems architecture / Software Engineering / Change Management / Project Management

Work experience

/ Statistics

/ Social sciences

Core:

NLP for French Banking Cie. – BPCE

Oct 2018 – Jun 2019

Year project with the BPCE banking group, within a group of 4 students. The objective is to create a database of labels commonly used by French companies to clarify banking labels, based on INSEE SIRET data. Worked on sparse and low quality data, data enrichment using different APIs (OpenStreetMap, Open Data), state of the art study on NLP techniques, and implementation of the latter (TF-IDF, Glove, RNN, LSTM, Embedding...)

Data Engineering Project – LesFurets.com *Dec 2018 - Jan 2019*

Implementation of a NoSQL cloud architecture (AWS) to process a large volume of data (3.5 TB). In groups of 5, we set up a MongoDB cluster with 12 machines (2 shards & replication factor : 3), using Spark on an Amazon EMR to pre-process the data. I was responsible for setting up the cluster on AWS and configuring it.

IT & Data Architecture Consultant – Wavestone Sep 2017 – Sep 2018

/ Study of issues related to Big Data, Graphs databases and NoSQL databases. In addition to mapping the different use cases, I made a PoC on Neo4J (in python) and a benchmark of the different Graph solutions.

/ Took part in various consulting missions for major French accounts (SNCF, ENEDIS, Ministry of the Army) on subjects related to Big Data, Machine Learning and the architecture of their IS.

Reinforcement Learning Project – IMT Atlantique Feb – Jun 2017

A 6-month project at IMT Atlantique, I participated in the agile production of 2 Als on the Snake game, using 2 distinct Reinforcement Learning techniques: Breeding for one, Q-Learning for the other. Use of Keras / Tensorflow.